Guide to the Bob Johnson Papers, 1949-2003 CTC.2014.03
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Pittsburgh Black Theatre Dance Ensemble and Theatre Urge, 1970-1985; V.
  - Finances, 1971-1982; 2.
    - National Endowment for the Arts (NEA) Grant, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 100)
    - Financial Report, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 101)
    - National Endowment for the Arts (NEA) Grant Correspondence, September 20, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 102)
    - Bicentennial Grant and Proposal, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 103-104)
    - Oliver Byrd Financial Management Contract and Report, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Annual Report, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Pennsylvania Council on the Arts Grants, 1976-1977 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - PACE Grant Applications, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Sears Roebuck Company Fall Festival Proposal, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Assorted Grant Applications, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Budget and Planning, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Howard Heinz Endowment, 1977-1979 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Theatre Urge Schedule and Budget, 1975-1977 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, Pennsylvania Council on the Arts, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Projected Costs, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Dance Ensemble, 1971-1985; 3.
    - Early Letterhead (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Brochure Draft (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Company Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - External Correspondence, 1971-1985 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Anonymous Letter from Company Member "H-6" (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Highlights of Spring Dance Concert "Free Spirit Song" by Robert LaPrince (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Damballah - The Ancient Vodu (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Johnson Choreographic Notes: Umbrella Dance Series, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Performance posters (Oversize), ca. 1975-1985 (Box 14, Oversize 21)
    - Performance posters (Oversize), ca. 1975-1980 (Map-case 25-6, Oversize 2)
    - Roots 77 Ballet Costume Designs (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Bicentennial Celebration, 1974-1976 (Box 6, Folder 21-23)
    - Notes and Essays, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Community Service Television Project (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Report on Contemporary Dance in Pittsburgh, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Production Material, Isis and Osiris (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Production Material, Natalie Sweet (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Contract Template (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Contracts, 1972-1977 (Box 6, Folder 30-31)
    - Performance and Rehearsal Schedules, 1974-1981 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Company Brochures and Flyers, ca. 1971-1979 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Performance Programs 'A-F', 1973-1981 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Performance Programs 'H-S', 1970-1981 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Performance Programs 'T-Y', 1970-1980 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Press Releases, ca. 1974-1980 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Press Clippings (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Press Clippings, 1970-1982 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Souvenir Programs, ca. 1975 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Afro American Dance Center, 1973-1980; 4.
    - Notes on the Afro American Dance Center (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - About the New Center, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Rules and Procedures (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Annual Report, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Certification of Completion (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Otis Sallid Residency, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Registration Flyers, 1974-1976 (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Seasonal Flyers and Programs, ca, 1974-1980 (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Press Clippings, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Theatre Urge, 1971-1985; 5.
    - Mission and Statement of Purpose (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - Correspondence, 1971-1985 (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - Finances, 1976-1977 (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - Proposal, Student Total Black Theatre Workshop (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - Schedule, 1976-1977 (Box 6, Folder 54)
    - Theatre Urge Reflections (Box 6, Folder 55)
    - American Fruit with African Roots, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - Production Material, Black Butter, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 57)
    - Production Material, Black Happenin' (Box 6, Folder 58)
    - Production Material, Chocolate Puddin' Proposal, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 59)
    - Production Material, Chocolate Puddin' Script, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 60)
    - Production Material, Chocolate Puddin' Fundraising Letter, 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 61)
    - Production Material, Chocolate Puddin' Correspondence, 1980-1982 (Box 6, Folder 62)
    - Production Material, Chocolate Puddin' Newsletter, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 63)
    - Production Material, Chocolate Puddin' Announcements, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 64)
    - Production Material, Chocolate Puddin' Schedule, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 65)
    - Production Material, Chocolate Puddin' Children Thank You Notes, 1980-1982 (Box 6, Folder 66-68)
    - Production Material, Chocolate Puddin' Logo, ca. 1981 (Box 6, Folder 69)
    - Production Material, Chocolate Puddin' Press, ca. 1980 (Box 6, Folder 70)
    - Production Material, The Fabulous Miss Marie (Box 6, Folder 71)
    - Production Material, Hello Out There| Baltimore| The Owl Killer, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 72)
    - Production Material, Hues of Langston, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 73)
    - Production Rights, Ladies in Waiting, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 74)
    - Script, Black Women Speak on Womenhood (Box 6, Folder 75)
    - Production Material, Can You Laff Martha (Box 6, Folder 76)
    - Script, Cause it's the Way We Feel Script by Parris J. Baker (Box 6, Folder 77)
    - Script, Ceremonies in Dark Old Men by Lonne Elder (Box 6, Folder 78)
    - Script, Cinder Box by L.M. Sullivan, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 79)
    - Script, The Eden Roc (Box 6, Folder 80)
    - Script, Harlem Dreams (Box 6, Folder 81)
    - Script, How Long has Niggahs Been Talking Shit??? or Are You Out of Your Cotton Pickin' Mind? by Derek Brooks and Gary Evans (Box 6, Folder 82)
    - Production Material, Judy's Monologue (Box 6, Folder 83)
    - Script, Junkes are Forever by Aubrey Bruce (Box 6, Folder 84)
    - The Legend of Marimba (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Script, Little Black Boys (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Script, Malcolm's Speech (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Script, Tears: The Living Children (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - TV Script, Tomorrow's Promise (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
    - Script, Uptown Backstreet (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Script, Woman in the Foxhole (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Script, Zenobia: Queen of the East (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Scripts, Untitled Scenes (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Performance Programs, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Performance posters (Oversize), ca. 1975-1976 (Box 14, Oversize 22)
    - Performance posters (Oversize), ca. 1975-1976 (Map-case 25-6, Oversize 2)
    - Press, Theatre Urge, ca. 1978-1981 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Photographs, 1970-1985; 6.
    - Pittsburgh Black Theatre Dance Ensemble, 1970-1985
      - Ritual of Damballah Solo at the 14th Annual Pittsburgh Folk Festival, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 17)
      - Dance Rehearsal Candids and Negatives, ca. 1970s (Box 12, Folder 18-27)
      - Performance Candids, Negatives and Slides, ca. 1970s (Box 12, Folder 28-36)
      - Politician Dance Performed at the Homeward Black Art Festival, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 37)
      - Outdoor Event and Performance, August 1972 (Box 12, Folder 38-39)
      - Traditional Medication Performance, ca. 1975 (Box 12, Folder 40)
      - Traditional Medication, Do it Anyway You Want, and I Shall Be Released Slides, ca. 1975 (Box 12, Folder 41)
      - Ritual of Damballah, ca. 1975 (Box 12, Folder 42)
      - Congregation Motion Shot and Choreography Notes, ca. 1975 (Box 12, Folder 43)
      - Performance photos, Many People Many Traditions calendar (Oversize), 1977 (Box 14, Folder 25)
      - Performance Candids and Slides, November 1977 (Box 12, Folder 44)
      - Three Rivers Art Festival with John Parks, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 45)
      - Performance Slides, June 1979 (Box 12, Folder 46)
      - Ritual of Damballah Photographs (Oversized), ca. 1970-1985 (Box 14, Folder 23)
      - Photographs (Oversized), ca. 1975 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Afro American Dance Center, 1974
      - Rehearsal Snapshot, ca. 1974 (Box 12, Folder 47)
      - Exposure I, ca. 1974 (Box 12, Folder 48)
      - Exposure II, ca. 1974 (Box 12, Folder 49)
      - Alvin Ailey Masterclass Slides, September 1974 (Box 12, Folder 50)
      - Performances, ca. 1979 (Box 12, Folder 51)
    - Theatre Urge, ca. 1970s
      - Unidentified Photoshoot and Bob Johnson TV Appearance Slides, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 52)
      - Black Happenin' Production Photographs, Negatives, and Slides, ca. 1975 (Box 12, Folder 53-59)
      - Ceremonies in Dark Old Men, ca. 1975 (Box 12, Folder 60)
      - Hues of Langston Candids, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 61)
      - American Fruit with African Roots Candids, Negatives, and Slides, ca. 1976-1978 (Box 12, Folder 62-65)
      - Miscellaneous Photographs and Negatives, ca. 1970s (Box 12, Folder 66-70)
- Teaching at the University of Pittsburgh, 1969-1986; VI.
  Items in this series relate to Mr. Johnson's 16-year tenure as in instructor in the University of Pittsburgh's Department of Africana Studies, known then as Black Studies. Materials include correspondence, departmental items, and teaching related content like course descriptions and syllabi, readings, and a small sample of student work. This material helps offer insight into Johnson's teaching methods.
  - Correspondence, 1969-1986; 1.
    - Germaine Acogny, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Jeanne Beaman, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Carl Beck, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Lloyd H. Bell, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Roger Benjamin, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Black Action Society, ca. 1970s (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Michael Boyd (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Dennis Brutus, 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Delores M. Cureton,Lemington Home for the Aged, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Carnegie Library of Pittsburgh, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Christian Associates, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Jack Daniel, 1971-1977 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Eugene Davis, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Michael Edwards, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Kathleen George, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Pam Hamlin, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Bruce Haselring, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - K. Leroy Irvis, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Vernell Lillie, 1981-1985 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Maliki El Muhajir, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Bayo Oduneye, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Rob Penny, 1978-1985 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Jane B. Robinson, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Jerome Rosenberg, 1977-1981 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Ronald Rothaus, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Barbara Sizemore, 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Rhoten Smith, 1978-1981 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Maxine Strawder, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Randy Strothman, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Upward Bound, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Urban League, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Robert Vee Van Parent Teacher Association, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Chineta White (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Administrative, 1970-1986; 2.
    - Black Studies Curriculum Development (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Proposal for Black Theatre Dance Workshop (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - First General Meeting of the Studio Theatre Poster (Oversized) (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Proposal for Summer Student Theatre Workshop, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Poster, Black Studies Department (Oversize), ca. 1970 (Map-case 25-6, Oversize 3)
    - Brazil Project, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - West African Dance Research, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - Draft, Research Grant for Afro-American Dance Manual (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - Caribbean Dance Project, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 52)
    - Teaching Afro-American Dance: A Multicultural Model, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - A Proposal for Facilitating The System-Wide Enrollment Magent School Plan for Desegregating the Pittsburgh Public Schools, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - Black Studies Department Cassette and Album Collection, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - India Trip, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 56)
    - Pittsburgh Public School Dance Curriculum, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 57)
    - African Heritage Studies Association Conference, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 58)
    - Posters, Black Action Society Events (Oversize), ca. 1980 (Map-case 25-6, Oversize 4)
    - Committee Report on Studio Theatre, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 59)
    - Sugar Cane Alley Project, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 60)
    - Submission of Course Info to CAS Committee on General Education in Humanities, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 61)
    - Talking Jazz Write-Up Draft, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 62)
    - Talking Jazz Proposal and Press, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 63)
    - Total Theatre: An Alternative to the Complexities of Urban Mis-Understanding, A Proposal Submitted to the Model Cities Cultural and Recreation Program (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - Black Horizon House of Kuumba: The Issue and The Solution, ca. 1971 (Box 7, Folder 65)
    - Kuntu Repertory Theatre, Production Materials, Do Lord Remember Me, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 66)
    - Kuntu Repertory Theatre, First draft reading script, Little Willie Armstrong Jones (Box 7, Folder 67)
    - Kuntu Repertory Theatre, Programs and other materials, 1975-1985 (Box 7, Folder 68)
    - Kuntu Repertory Theatre, Ma Rainey's Black Bottom program signed by August Wilson, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 69)
    - Kuntu Repertory Theatre, Script, Just Rob Penny: Black Tones of Truth (Box 7, Folder 70)
    - Kuntu Repertory Theatre performance posters (Oversize), 1984-1985 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Kuntu Writers Workshop, 1976-1985 (Box 7, Folder 71)
    - Black Student Handbook (Box 7, Folder 72)
    - Black Dance Lecture/Performance Report Form, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 73)
    - Evaluation of Roller Skating Dance Workshop, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 74)
    - Teaching Proposals (Box 7, Folder 75)
    - Dr. Vernell Lille- Adaption of A Dream Deferred, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 76)
    - Black American Poetry Reading at the Wilkinsburg Public Library, February 25, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 77)
    - Speech Communication Association Conference presentation on Black Dance, December 1976 (Box 7, Folder 78)
  - Classes, 1972-1985; 3.
    - Readings, 1972-1985
      - Black Dance in America: The Deep Root and Strong Branch (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Course Readings (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Excerpts, Jazz Dance: The Story of American Vernacular Dance by Marshall Stearns (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Blues for Blacks in Hollywood by Cecil Brown, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Excerpt, God Wills the Negro; An Anthropological and Geographical Restoration of the Lost History of the American Negro People (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Kwanza- The First Fruits: An African Holiday by The Congress of African People, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Reading on Acting Technique (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Reading on Astrology (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Folk Music Research in Jamaica by Olive Lewin, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - The Acting and The Actors (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Excerpt, Scriptwriting for the Audio-Visual Media by Robert Edmonds, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - Excerpt, Dance and Movement Readings, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - Melvin Van Peebles Lyrics (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - Essence Magazine Article, Broadway's New Breed, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - Jet Magazine Article, Is there a Future for Black Talent in the Theatre?, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Course Descriptions, Syllabi, and Assignments, 1972-1985
      - Development and Overview of Kuumba Theatre Workshop (Box 8, Folder 16)
      - Creativity Workshop Description with notes from Rob Penny (Box 8, Folder 17)
      - Kuumba Performance Flyer, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 18)
      - Kuumba Bicentennial Project, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 19)
      - Kuumba Ugly Contest Poster, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 20)
      - Kuumba Theatre Workshop C-H-A-N-G-E Assignment, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 21)
      - Kuumba Theatre Workshop Class Development Notes, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 22)
      - Kuumba Theatre Workshop: A Vintage Wine Quiz and Answers, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 23)
      - Kuumba Theatre Workshop Syllabi, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 24)
      - Kuumba Theatre Workshop Assignments and Exams, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 25)
      - Chocolate Puddin' Poster and Sketch (Box 8, Folder 26)
      - Kuumba Theatre Workshop Syllabus, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 27)
      - Kuumba Theatre Workshop/Creativity Workshop Final Project, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 28)
      - Kuumba Theatre Workshop, Script: 'A Love Rap in Funkytown' (Box 8, Folder 29)
      - Kuumba Theatre Workshop, Why Black Studies Dialogue (Box 8, Folder 30)
      - Kuumba Theatre Workshop, Pittsburghers Against Apartheid (Box 8, Folder 31)
      - Kuumba Theatre Workshop, American Fruit with African Roots (Box 8, Folder 32)
      - Afro American Dance Expression Course Lectures (Box 8, Folder 33)
      - Afro American Dance Expression Course Proposal (Box 8, Folder 34)
      - Revolutionary Theatre Workshop (Box 8, Folder 35)
      - Afro American Dance Expression Syllabi, 1972-1980 (Box 8, Folder 36)
      - Afro American Dance Expression Video Tapes, 1972-1973 (Box 8, Folder 37)
      - Afro American Dance Expression: Black Light Explosion, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 38)
      - Afro American Dance Expression Final Exam Programs, 1979-1983 (Box 8, Folder 39)
      - Afro American Dance Final Information Form, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 40)
      - Syllabus, Movement for Actors (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Student Work, 1973-1985
      Access Restrictions
      In compliance with FERPA regulations, the material in this series is restricted. To access material in this section, the researcher must agree to sign a confidentiality agreement provided by Special Collections.
      - Kuumba Theatre/Creativity Workshop, 1973-1975 (Box 8, Folder 42-47)
      - Kuumba Theatre/Creativity Workshop, 1977-1980 (Box 8, Folder 48-57)
      - Kuumba Theatre/Creativity Workshop, 1982-1986 (Box 8, Folder 58-68)
      - Kuumba Theatre/Creativity Workshop (Box 8, Folder 69-73)
      - Afro American Dance Expression, 1973-1982 (Box 8, Folder 74-82)
  - Photographs, 1971-1985; 4.
    - "Save Me" Beltzhoover Dance Group University of Pittsburgh Project Self-Esteem, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 71)
    - Dance Expression Class Candids and Negatives, ca. 1971-1985 (Box 12, Folder 72-79)
    - Creativity Workshop Candids and Slides, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 80)
    - Leisure Learn Program, ca. 1975 (Box 12, Folder 81)
    - Black Studies Department Candids and Slides, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 82)
    - Michelle Wallace Lecture Slides, November 1979 (Box 12, Folder 83)
    - BCOHE, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 84)
    - Chocolate Puddin' Photographs and Slides, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 85-86)
    - Talking Jazz Candids and Negatives, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 87)
    - Rob Penny, ca. 1985 (Box 12, Folder 88)
- Black Arts Movement Performing Arts Scripts and Ephemera, 1966-1990; VII.
  The material in this series contains theatre scripts, performing arts newsletters, and dance company ephemera of artists and performers of the Black Arts Movement. These artists and performers were from both Pittsburgh and elsewhere in the United States. The series has scripts from Amiri Baraka such as A Black Mass and Columbia Gem of the Ocean, Rob Penny's, Centre Avenue: A Trip and Dance of the Blues Dead, several plays by William F. Mayfield, and August Wilson's The Coldest Day of the Year. There are also a number of scripts by local playwrights such as William F. Mayfield's Black Sci- Fi Saga. The series also contains newsletters from The Black Theatre Alliance and Dance Herald, and The Feet, as well as ephemera from the Chuck Davis, Author Hall, and Eleo Pomare dance companies among others.
  - Scripts, 1966-1990; 1.
    This subseries of scripts is arranged alphabetically by the author's last name.
    - Al Grover Armstrong, The Essence of Suicide (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Lamont Arnold and Patrick Roche, Trumpets of Gabriel (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Amiri Baraka, A Black Mass, ca. 1966 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Amiri Baraka, Columbia The Gem of the Ocean (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Lorenzo Lo Boone and Greg Quick Evans, Glitter/Lucifer's Trap, ca. 1974 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Gary Bradford, Give the Drummer Some, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Gary Bradford, The Inverted Pyramid (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Gary Bradford, King Solomon Minds, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - William F. Brown and Charlie Smalls, The Wiz, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Gary C. Evans, Confusion (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Alex Foster, Community Kitchen (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - GEO, Ravings (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Bill Harris, Stories About the Old Days, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Susan Marcus, Linda Marcus, and Ken Wishnia, Sometimes I Feel Like Raggady Anne, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - William F. Mayfield, Catfish Murder: An Adult Fantasy, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - William F. Mayfield, Black Theatre Entrepreneur (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - William F. Mayfield, Little Black Boys, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - William F. Mayfield, Little Black Boys with annotations, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - William F. Mayfield, Little Black Boys with audio cassette, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - William F. Mayfield, Morphis, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - William F. Mayfield, Playwriting for Black Theatre, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - William F. Mayfield, Queen Bee, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - William F. Mayfield, Osiris, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - William F. Mayfield, Spirits of Water, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - William F. Mayfield, Sing Black Hammer, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - William F. Mayfield, A Vintage Wine, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - William F. Mayfield, WIlli T: A Janitor in the Andromeda Galaxy Spawns a New Civilization, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Paulette Pennington-Jones, State of Grace Segment (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Rob Penny, Centre Avenue, A Trip (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Rob Penny, Coon Cane (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Rob Penny, Dance of the Blues Dead (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Rob Penny, Diane's Heart Dries Out Still More (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Rob Penny, Liferise (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Rob Penny, Little Willie Armstrong Jones (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Rob Penny, Sugar and Thomas (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Rob Penny, Up to Life (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Curtiss Porter, Rappingstone (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - James T. Stewart, Five Plays for Children (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - S. McLain Thomas and Michael D. Lies, A Man Called Christ, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - LaVerne Tribble, The Plantation (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Paul Weinman, The Bite (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - August Wilson, The Coldest Day of the Year (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - August Wilson, The Homecoming (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Unknown Author, Noir Saga (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Unknown Author, Untitled (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Newsletters, 1971-1986; 2.
    - Black Masks, A Theatre Arts Publication, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - The Black Scholar v.10 no. 10, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Black Stage Magazine, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Black Theatre, ca. 1968-1970 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - The Black Theatre Alliance Touring Brochure (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Black Theatre Alliance Newsletter, 1977-1979 (Box 10, Folder 19-21)
    - Dance Herald: A Journal of Black Dance, 1975-1979 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - The Feet, 1971-1973 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Photo Newsletter: James Van Derzee Institute, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Dance Newsletters and clippings, ca. 1969-1982 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Company Ephemera, 1966-1983; 3.
    - Poster, The 127th Street Repertory Ensemble (Oversized), ca. 1980 (Map-case 25-6, Oversize 1)
    - Poster, The Alvin Ailey American Dance Theater (Oversized), ca. 1969 (Map-case 25-6, Oversize 1)
    - Arthur Hall's Afro American Dance Ensemble, ca.1974-1975 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Poster, Arthur Hall's Afro American Dance Ensemble (Oversize), ca. 1974 (Map-case 25-6, Oversize 1)
    - Poster, Black Dance Institute of San Francisco Inc., 1975 (Map-case 25-6, Oversize 1)
    - Poster, Black Horizon Theatre (Oversize), ca. 1971 (Map-case 25-6, Oversize 3)